Guide to the Paul Langland Papers, 1926-2018 MSS.253
Fales Library and Special Collections
Paul Langland Papers
1926-2018
Fales Library and Special Collections
Langland, Paul
MSS.253
60 Linear Feet in 61 containers
6 Gigabytes in 33 computer files
Paul Langland is a choreographer, dancer and educator. The Paul Langland Papers contain paper and electronic files related to Langland's projects, performances, teaching, and professional involvement with modern dance techniques, including Allan Wayne Work and Contact Improvisation, from the mid-1970s through 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection was originally donated in 2009, with additional donations in 2010, 2013, 2014, 2015-2017, and 2018.
Appraisal
Two CD-Rs were removed from the collection, considered by a curator to be outside the collection policies of Special Collections:
Reefer Blues: Vintage Songs About Marijuana
Meredith Monk Piano Songs
Arrangement Note
This collection is arranged into 13 series as follows:
Series I: Files
Series II: Notebooks and Planners
Series III: Photographs
Series IV: Posters, Programs, and Flyers
Series V: Allan Wayne Material
Series VI: Video Recordings
Series VII: Sound Recordings
Series VIII: Vinyl Sound Recordings
Series IX: Data Storage
Series X: Objects
Series XI: 2015 Accretion
Series XII: 2016-2017 Accretions
Series XIII: 2018 Accretion
Material is arranged both chronologically and alphabetically in different series, in some cases to retain the original organization. The materials in Series XI: 2015 Accretion, Series XII. 2016-2017 Accretions, and Series XIII. 2018 Accretion have not been arranged by an archivist and are in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Paul Langland is a choreographer, dancer and educator. Langland received his BFA in Sculpture and Performance from the California College of Arts and Crafts in 1973. While in California, Langland began his involvement with the Contact Improvisation dance technique, studying under its founder Steve Paxton.
After moving to New York City in the 1970s, Langland began working with choreographer and performer Meredith Monk, whose company he later joined. Langland remained a member of the Meredith Monk Vocal Ensemble until 1985.
During his time in New York City, Langland also studied closely under dancer Allan Wayne. After Wayne's death in 1978, Langland began teaching his technique, under the name "Allan Wayne Work," and continued to develop his work.
Throughout his career, Langland has performed at various notable performance spaces and with various performance groups including The House, Danspace, Dance Theater Workshop, LaMama, The Kitchen, and Franklin Furnace, among others. Langland has also held a number of fellowships and residencies, leading to performances and workshops throughout North America, Europe, Korea, Venezuela and Cuba. He is currently a master teacher at New York University's Experimental Theater Wing.
Choreography Timeline
1984 Fame and Money, Performance Space 122, New York City
1983-1986 Channel Z, Movement Research, New York City
1986 Rapture, Danspace at St. mark's Church, New York City
1989 Boomerang, University of Alabama Boneyard, Performance Space 122, New York City
1990 Full Flora Smak, Ballet Academy, Gottenburg, Sweeden The Ghost of a Flea, Performance Space 122, New York City Jonah, Spectra Arts, New York City
1991 Normal Kansas, New York University Experimental Theather Wing and International Theater School Festival, Amsterdam
1992 In The Field, New York University Experimental Theater Wing
1994 Full Flora Smak (new version), New York University Experimental Theater Wing
1996 Normal Dog Time, DanceFest 6 at Columbia-Greene College, New York City
1998 Honor, Danspace at Saint Mark's Church, New York City Almost Rapture, Dancespace at Saint Mark's Church, New York City
2000 Heat, Movement Research at Judson Church, New York City
2001 Rooms and Buildings (Collaboration with Mary Overlie and Wendell Beavers), Judson Church, New York City Getting Ready to Really Leave, Amherst College Dance Institute, Massachusetts
2003 Storyteller, University Settlement, New York City Self-Erasure (Collaboration with Dana Salisbury), Here Theater, New York City
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Scope and Contents
The Paul Langland Papers contain material created and collected by Paul Langland during the course of his career as a choreographer, dancer and educator. The collection documents in paper and electronic files his performance and teaching of contemporary dance techniques, including Allan Wayne Work (for which Langland is a main developer) and Contact Improvisation. There is also documentation of Langland's personal works, as well as his contributions to various dance ensembles, with a focus on those located in New York City.
Material includes choreography notes, journals, artist and project files, flyers, programs, posters, and records related to Langland's tenure as a professor at New York University's Tisch School of the Arts. Additionally, the collection includes photographs documenting Langland's projects, tours, and personal life. Also included in the collection are original video and film recordings of Langland's performances. Sound recordings may be unavailable until reformating occurs.
Contact improvisation.; Modern dance.; Dance photography.; Notebooks; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Reviews (document genre); Audiotapes.; Videocassettes.; Fliers (printed matter); Posters.; Long-playing records.; Monk, Meredith; Langland, Paul; Wayne, Allan
- Series I: Files, 1966-2011
  Scope and Content
  Series I consists of files kept by Paul Langland on various performances, artists and subjects. It includes correspondence, artist's files, programs and promotional material, press, interviews, and production information. Additionally, it includes choreography notes both for Langland's personal performances and original choreography, as well as performances associated with his position in NYU's Experimental Theater Wing. Much of the material is related to Paul Langland's involvement in the developement, teaching and performance of the "Allan Wayne Work" and Contact Improvisation dance techniques. This largely includes class notes and information on workshops and conferences, as well as information on various fellowships and residencies held by Paul Langland.
  Arrangement Note
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by folder title. Titles are original unless otherwise noted.
  - All Studio AIDS Event, 1992; cuid28940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allan Wayne Article, 1996; cuid28941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Almost Rapture, 1997; cuid28942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Almost Rapture Notes, 1997-1999; cuid28943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American College Dance Festival Association - ACOFA/AOF [1 of 2], 1989-1990; cuid28944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American College Dance Festival Association - ACOFA/AOF [2 of 2], 1989-1990; cuid28945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Dance Festival - ADF Seoul [1 of 2], 1991; cuid28946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Dance Festival - ADF Seoul [2 of 2], 1991; cuid28947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Antigone Program - Judson's Poet Theater, 1966; cuid28948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Article and Poster Samples, 1992; 1995-1997; undated; cuid28949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Autobiography of a Liar, 1999; cuid28950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Boneyard, 1989; cuid28951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Boomerang, undated; cuid28952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - California Performances, 2003; cuid28953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Channel Z, 1984-1986; 2008; cuid28954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chicago Tour Documents, 1982; cuid28955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Choreography/Workshops, 2000-2009; cuid28956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Class Notes, 1982; cuid28957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Class Addresses, 1980-1987; cuid28958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cliffs of Desperes, 1996; cuid28959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Collaborations, 2002-2008; cuid28960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Connecticut College CITE Conference, 2010; cuid28961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - C.I. 36 Conference of Contact Improvisation, 2008; cuid28962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - C.I. [Contact Improvisation] Ground Research - Earth Dance, 2010; cuid28963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Contact Improv, 1976-1977; undated; cuid28964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Contact Improv [1 of 2], 2008; undated; cuid28965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Contact Improv [2 of 2], 2008; undated; cuid28966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Contact Article, 1997-2000; cuid28967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Contactfestival - Freiburg, Germany, 2010; cuid28968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Contact Quarterly, 1995; cuid28969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cornell/Amherst, 1998-1999; cuid28970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Course Descriptions, 1994; undated; cuid28971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Croft/Vaughn [show outline], undated; cuid28972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Dance Contracts, 1978-1979; 1981-1982; 1984; 1986-1991; undated; cuid28973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dance on the Square [Almost Rapture], 1998; cuid28974 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Dance Material [1 of 2], 1979; 1982-1991; 1995-1998; 2000-2001; undated; cuid28975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dance Material [2 of 2], 1979; 1982-1991; 1995-1998; 2000-2001; undated; cuid28976 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Domestic Virtue, 1988; cuid28977 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Downtown/Upstate, 1989-1990; cuid28978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Downtown/Upstate performer photos, cuid28979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Drama Therapy Conference, 1997; cuid28980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Experimental Theater Wing Graduation Photos and Class Lists, 1992; 2002; 2004; 2011; cuid28981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Eddie, undated; cuid28982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Edinburgh Fringe, Ricky DeMarco Student Workshop, 1973; cuid28983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ephemera, 1984; undated; cuid28984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fame and Money, 1984; cuid28985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Festival International de Theatre Bruxelles, 1979; cuid28986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Full Flora Smak, 1994-1995; cuid28987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fuse Festival, 2003; cuid28988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Germany, 1986; cuid28989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gertrude Stein Octoberfest [Rooms and Buildings], 2002; cuid28990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Getting Ready to Really Leave, 2002; cuid28991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Ghost of a Flea, 1990; cuid28992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Guerilla Performances, undated; cuid28993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Heat, 2000; cuid28994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hello Big Honey, undated; cuid28995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Honda HD, 1987; cuid28996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Honor, 1999; cuid28997 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Honor Notes, 1998; cuid28998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Honor Costume Design - Kitty Leach, 1998; cuid28999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Humbolt's Current (Ping Chong), 1977-1978; cuid29000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Interviews, 1981; 1989; cuid29001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - I will not be...[sad in this life], 2008; cuid29002 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Jonah, 1990-1991; cuid29003 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - [Joseph Langland], 1981; 2000; 2007; cuid29004 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Jungle Breath, undated; cuid29005 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - La Mama 50th Anniversary Gala, 2010-2011; cuid29006 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Letters- Dance [1 of 4], 1970-1988; cuid29007 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Letters- Dance [2 of 4], 1970-1988; cuid29008 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Letters- Dance [3 of 4], 1979-1988; cuid29009 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Letters- Dance [4 of 4], 1991-2000; cuid29010 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Letters- Dance Related [1 of 2], 1985-1996; cuid29011 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Letters- Dance Related [2 of 2], cuid29012 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Letters- Paul Langland responses, 1992; 2002-2009; undated; cuid29013 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Letters- Performing Arts and Dancing [1 of 2], 2000-2010; cuid29014 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letters- Performing Arts and Dancing [2 of 2], 2000-2010; cuid29015 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letters- Teaching, 1991-2001; cuid29016 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Meredith Monk, 1976; 1980-1983; 1989-1990; 2000; undated; cuid29017 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Meredith Monk, 1974-1982; cuid29018 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Meredith Monk Choreography Notes, undated; cuid29019 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Meredith Monk Company Documents, 1980; undated; cuid29020 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Meredith Monk Company Press Clippings, 1976-1979; 1981-1983; 2000, 2005, 2009-2010; cuid29021 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Meredith Monk Photographs, undated; cuid29022 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Meredith Monk- Reviews, 1976-1979; 1981-1984; 1987; cuid29023 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Methodologies Outline, undated; cuid29024 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Meyerhold, 1973; cuid29025 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous [Press and Notes], 2000-2010; cuid29026 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Montreal, 1996; cuid29027 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Movement Research, 1984-1989; cuid29028 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Movement Research [1 of 2], 2000-2006; cuid29029 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Movement Research [2 of 2], 2000-2006; cuid29030 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Movement Research Spring Gala, 2011; cuid29031 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Movement Research Studies Project, 1984; cuid29032 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Naropa Institute, 2005; cuid29033 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Normal Kansas, 1991; cuid29034 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - New York Dance & Performance Awards, 1985-1991; cuid29035 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - NYPL Oral Histories Project, 2002-2004; cuid29036 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - [NYU]- Distinguished Master Teacher Committee, 2000-2003; cuid29037 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - NYU Experimental Theater Wing, 1983-1985; cuid29038 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - [NYU]- Letters to Paul Langland, 2001; 2003; 2009; cuid29039 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - [NYU]- The Performing Body in Theory and Practice Class Syllabus, 2009; cuid29040 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NYU Spousal Benefits Project [1 of 2], 1992-1994; cuid29041 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - NYU Spousal Benefits Project [2 of 2], 1992-1994; cuid29042 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - [NYU]- Spousal Benefits/Domestic Partnership, 1993; cuid29043 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - [NYU]- Spousal Benefits/Association of Lesbian and Gay Faculty, Administrators and Staff (ALGFS), 1993-1994; cuid29044 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Outfall, 1993-1995; cuid29045 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Paul Langland Biography, undated; cuid29046 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Paul Langland Press/Articles, 1995; 2001; 2004-2005; 2009; 2010-2011; undated; cuid29047 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Paul Langland Press to 2008, 1976-1979; 1981-1991; 1997-2005; cuid29048 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Personal Notes, 2011; cuid29049 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Paula Cooper Gallery Photos of Drawings, 1977; cuid29050 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Professional Activity, 2010; cuid29051 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Progetto Shakespeare/Project Shakespeare, 1979; 1982; cuid29052 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Rapture, undated; cuid29053 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [Retazos/Danza Teatro], 1994-1995; cuid29054 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - [Retazos/Danza Teatro Cuba Grant], 1996; cuid29055 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reviews, 1977; 1984-1986; 1994; cuid29056 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Reviews, 1976-1977; 1980-1986; 1989-1990; 1993-1997; cuid29057 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reviews, 1984; 1986; 1989-1990; cuid29058 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Reviews- Mary Overlie, 1978; cuid29059 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Richard Armstrong Voice Workshop, 2008; 2011; cuid29060 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Scott Heron, undated; cuid29061 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Surface, undated; cuid29062 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - SUNY- Partners Annual Dance Festival, 1989; cuid29063 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - SUNY Programs in the Arts, 1986; 1989-1990; cuid29064 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Southern Tour, 1989; cuid29065 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sweden, 1990; cuid29066 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - [The Thinking Body - Photocopies], undated; cuid29067 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - [Diane] Torr, 1987; cuid29068 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Universite de Genève, 1983; cuid29069 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Upstate Dance Projects, 1981-1989; cuid29070 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Venezula Dance Festival, 1990; cuid29071 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Visual Art and Film, 1981-1982; 1986-1989; 1992-1993; 1998; undated; cuid29072 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Willoughby Nursing Home, 1978; cuid29073 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Waterfall, undated; cuid29074 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Whoopee in the Dark, 2002; cuid29075 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Whoopee in the Dark/Dana Salisbury, 2002; cuid29076 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Yoshi Yoara Christmas Cards to members of [Meredith] Monk Company, undated; cuid29077 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Series II: Notebooks and Planners, 1973-2009
  Series II is arranged chronologically within each type of material. Notebooks are dated by the earliest date included.
  Series II consists of personal notebooks and planners. They include personal information as well as information related to Paul Langland's choreography and
  - Notebook, 1973; cuid29078 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Notebook- Bonnie Cohen, 1978; cuid29079 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, February 1978-April 1978; January 1981-January 1983; cuid29080 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, July 1984-October 1985; cuid29081 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, October 1985-September 1986; cuid29082 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, 1986-1988; cuid29083 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, September 1986-April 1987; cuid29084 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, March 1988-June 1988; cuid29085 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, June 1988-February 1989; cuid29086 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, August 1989-September 1990; cuid29087 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, 1990; cuid29088 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, October 1992-November 1993; cuid29089 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, 1992-1993; cuid29090 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, February 1994-March 1995; cuid29091 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, September 1996-July 1996; cuid29092 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, 1996-1997; cuid29093 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, October 1997-April 1998; cuid29094 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, November 1998-January 2000; cuid29095 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Notebook, January 2000-November 2000; cuid29096 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Notebook- Class Notes, January 2001-October 2001; cuid29097 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Notebook, October 2001-October 2002; March 2003; cuid29098 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Notebook- Naropa Institute, undated; cuid29099 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, undated; cuid29100 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Notebook, undated; cuid29101 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Notebook, undated; cuid29102 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Notebook, undated; cuid29103 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Notebook, undated; cuid29104 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Calendar, 1978; cuid29105 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Date Book, 1979-1980; cuid29106 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Date Book, 1981; 1982; cuid29107 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Date Book, 1983; 1984; cuid29108 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Date Book, 1985; 1986; cuid29109 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Date Book, Jaunary-December 1987; cuid29110 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Date Book, July 1991-August 1992; cuid29111 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Date Book, September 1992-August 1993; cuid29112 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Date Book, August 1993-August 1994; cuid29113 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Date Book, August 1994-Auguest 1995; cuid29114 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Date Book, August 1995-August 1996; cuid29115 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Date Book, August 1996-August 1997; cuid29116 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Date Book, September 1997-September 1998; cuid29117 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Date Book, September 1998-September 1999; cuid29118 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Date Book, September 1999-October 2000; cuid29119 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Date Book, October 2000-October 2001; cuid29120 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Date Book, October 2001-October 2002; cuid29121 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Date Book, October 2002-October 2003; cuid29122 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Date Book, October 2003-October 2004; cuid29123 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Date Book, October 2008-September 2009; cuid29124 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Series III: Photographs, 1965-2011
  Series III consists of both dance related and personal photographs. The majority of the photographs document Paul Langand's tours with various dance ensembles, most notably with Meredith Monk's company. It includes many photographs of dance performances and events, as well as some promotional photographs for individual pieces. It also includes personal photographs that document New York City and various vacations.
  Series III is arranged chronologically by the earliest date in each section. Binder 17 reflects two photo albums kepy by Paul Langland.
  - Dance Related Photographs, 1965; 1976; 1982-2001; 2009; 2011; cuid29125 (Binder 7)
  - Meredith Monk, 1971-1980; 1984; 1987; cuid29126 (Binder 7)
    General
    25 photographs, 1 slide
  - Artists in Process Workshop, 1973-1974; cuid29127 (Binder 7)
    5 photographs
  - Contact Improv, 1973; 1978; cuid29128 (Binder 7)
    18 photographs
  - Paula Cooper Gallery, 1975-1980; 1983; 1986; 1998-2001; 2008; cuid29129 (Binder 7)
    4 photographs
  - Assorted Dance Photographs, cuid29130 (Binder 7)
    9 photographs
  - Skin, 1976; cuid29131 (Binder 8)
    71 photographs, 1 contact sheet, 1 page negatives
  - Meredith Monk Company Photographs, 1977; 1980; 1982; 1989; 1993; 2009; cuid29132 (Binder 8)
  - Meredith Monk Tour- Texas, 1978; cuid29133 (Binder 8)
    5 photographs, 1 sheet of negatives
  - Meredith Monk Tour- Texas/Colorado, 1978; cuid29134 (Binder 8)
    2 pages of negatives
  - Contact Improvisation at Paula Cooper Gallery, 1978; cuid29135 (Binder 8)
    33 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Contact Quarterly Benefit- Cunningham Studios, NYC, 1978; cuid29136 (Binder 9)
  - Ping Chong, 1979; 2002; cuid29137 (Binder 9)
  - Assorted Dance Photographs, 1979; 1983; 1984; 1986; 1988; 1990; 1991;1997-1999; 2008; 2009; cuid29138 (Binder 9)
    22 photographs, 3 negatives
  - Meredith Monk Tour- Taormina, 1979; cuid29139 (Binder 9)
    3 photographs, 4 pages of negatives
  - Meredith Monk Tour, Travelogue Series- Los Angeles, 1979; cuid29140 (Binder 9)
    2 pages of negatives [Negatives only - see Binder 11 (Album) for related photographs]
  - Contact Concert at Paula Cooper Gallery Photo Shoot, 1979; cuid29141 (Binder 9)
  - Gay Pride- New York City, Washington D.C., Amsterdam, 1979; 1986; 1992; 1998; 2000; cuid29142 (Binder 9)
    17 photographs
  - [New York City, Cabin in Vermont, Colin Cochran Studio Shots, Prince Philip], 1980; 1989; 1992-1994; 1998-1999; 2005; 2009; cuid29143 (Binder 9)
    22 photographs
  - Bread and Puppet Theater- Vermont, 1982; cuid29144 (Binder 9)
    46 photographs
  - Tour to Geneva, 1982; cuid29145 (Binder 10)
    6 photographs
  - Meredith Monk Tour- Specimen Days, 1982; cuid29146 (Binder 10)
    3 photographs
  - Turtle Dreams- PBS Geneva, 1982; cuid29147 (Binder 10)
    27 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Turtle Dreams TV Shoot- Springfield, MA, 1982; cuid29148 (Binder 10)
    7 photographs
  - Meredith Monk Company- New York, Italy, 1982; cuid29149 (Binder 10)
    32 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Meredith Monk Tour, New Music Festival- Chicago, 1982; cuid29150 (Binder 10)
  - Scarf Dance, 1982; cuid29151 (Binder 10)
    2 contact sheets
  - Allan Wayne Work, 1982; cuid29152 (Binder 10)
    7 contact sheets
  - East Meredith [New York], 1983; cuid29153 (Binder 10)
    2 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Salome at Pyramid Club, 1983; cuid29154 (Binder 10)
    25 photographs
  - Channel Z, 1983; cuid29155 (Binder 10)
    3 photographs, 1 negative